Julien Bertazzo Lambert

204.232.7354 jbertazzolambert@gmail.com Toronto, Ontario, M5B 2G3

♣ https://julienbl.me

in https://linkedin.com/in/julien-bl

Summary

Bilingual (French/English) aspiring software engineer experienced in creating full stack applications and working in a team setting.

- Created 3 full-stack web applications using React/Node.js/MongoDB for school projects, personal projects, and hackathons.
- Provided customer service in French and English for 3 years, working in a team setting at Cineplex Entertainment and at American Campus Communities.

Technologies

Proficient: JavaScript, Java, Python, HTML, CSS, C, React, Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, Google Cloud API

Exposure: Mongoose, Socket.io, C++

Projects

Meal Planner | Full Stack Web App | https://github.com/JLambertazzo/MealPlanner | 2021 Web application to help users plan out their meals and their shopping, saving them time and money.

- Created backend using Express.js for API routing, MongoDB as database, run on Node.js.
- Designed a simple, responsive frontend using React & Material-UI.
- Supported proper data storage using Mongoose Schemas.

ListExtender.js | Frontend JS Library | https://github.com/JLambertazzo/ListExtender | 2020 JavaScript library providing intuitive, interactive lists with easy implementation.

- Designed the library to offer interactive lists without polluting the global namespace.
- Created a web site to provide examples and documentation using HTML/CSS/JavaScript.

ZoomLoader | Full Stack Web App | https://github.com/JLambertazzo/ZoomLoader | 2020 Web application designed to manage a user's zoom meetings – submission for First Day Back Hacks 2020.

- Created backend using Socket.io for communication, MongoDB as database, run on Node.js.
- Design simple, elegant frontend using Bootstrap.

FinderBot | Discord Bot | https://github.com/JLambertazzo/FinderBot | 2020 Discord Bot querying Google Cloud API to search places – submission for Suns Out Hacks Out 2020

- Created the bot using Discord.js package for Node.js.
- Set up Google Cloud API account and links to send and handle requests.

Work Experience

2019 - 2020

Community Assistant | American Campus Communities | Toronto, Ontario

- Organized, marketed, and executed building-wide and floor-wide events, working in a team setting, resulting in greater engagement with residents and greater reach for future events.
- Provided customer service in French and English to residents at front desk and while on call.

2017 - 2019

Cast Member | Cineplex Entertainment | Winnipeg, Manitoba

- Provided customer service in French and English at concession stand, ticketing booth, and while hosting birthday parties.
- Lead team of cast members to ensure work was done properly and on time.
- Handled guest concerns in a timely manner.

Volunteer Experience

2020 - 2021

Marketing Director | UofT Web Dev Club | Toronto, Ontario

- Grew online presence of the UofT Web Dev Club, reaching over 200 people through 4 different channels (Instagram, Facebook, LinkedIn, Discord).
- Planned posts and marketing strategies to promote events and projects going on within the UofT Web Dev Club.
- Created marketing graphics to go along with posts about events and projects.

Education

Bachelor of Science – September 2019 – May 2023

- University of Toronto St. George Campus, Toronto, Ontario
- Double Major in Mathematics and Economics
- Maintaining a GPA above 3.5